Hi from Tokyo again
this is my second week back in Tokyo
one thing I’ve noticed since coming back
is that there definitely a lot more people
I heard over tourism have been an issue
so this week I’m trying to explore the quieter neighbourhoods of Tokyo
starting off, we’re at Nippori
from here we’ll be walking to Yanaka Ginza
which is a traditional area of Tokyo
filled with traditional wooden houses, izakaya and retro coffee shops
you can also find local restaurants, sweets and handicrafts store
the area is also well known for it’s senbei
you can smell the fresh senbei walking past
lunch is at this kissaten
this cafe is well over 70 years old
I recommend making a reservation, since they have a no waiting policy
but luckily it wasn’t too busy when I went
I got a melon soda and their egg sandwich set
this is a must get at this store
this was the most fluffy egg and the bread was somehow chewy
I would come back just for this sandwich
time to look around more of the neighbourhood
there are also a lot of craft stores in the area
they have such a cute selection of things
but there is one area I wanted to check out
here you can find a collaboration of small shops and cafes in and old traditional household
starting with this craft beer store
there are also a few art-craft shops
and a bakery that sells bread and sweets
this fig and chocolate one sounds so good
grabbed a few so that I can have them for breakfast
I was going to get some coffee here but the cafe was closed for today
so we’ll continue our walk to the main area of Yanaka
Yanaka is also interestingly known as the ‘Cat town’
not quite sure why but there are so many cat themed shops here
they have good coffee and brunch options
the coffee was great as usual
the staff are always super friendly and welcoming too
the cafe also has some homewares and goods for sale
this is the main Yanaka shopping street
definitely a must visit for any cat lovers
I think you can find some fun souvenirs here as well
how cute are these chopstick holders
and of course some Kiki merch
getting one more treat before heading off
there’s so many options
but can’t go wrong with the original
let’s go grabs some dinner
the flagship store in Asakusa is huge
another food I missed the most is definitely sushi!
highly recommend this broccoli prawn salad
it doesn’t look that promising but it’s really yummy
and the corn tempura is really good as well
late night snack time watching Bridgerton
couldn’t wait this morning to try my carrot cupcake
best way to end the night
trying my fig and chocolate bread
preparing some yogurt while I toast that up
got some frozen mangos the other day
this was such a good combo
the weather is so clear today
so we’re going to go check out another cute neighbourhood in Tokyo
did I choose this place for the name?
maybe...
but they are also well known for their coffee
they hand-pick their own original beans and roast them twice
resulting in a really smooth and refreshing taste
love this magazine for cafe recommendations
the area we’re going to check out today is Kuramae
which is considered the 'Brooklyn' of Tokyo
the area is known for its artisan community
and is home to small manufacturers and craft stores
this stationery shop is popular for their customisable notebooks
you can customise everything from the cover to which paper you want
they also had some other stationaries
they were also giving out this map of the area
it showed all the fun shops and restaurants to visit
so let’s go visit some of these shops
this is both a cafe and a chocolate factory
these would be such great presents
and everything is made in house
they have so many hot chocolate options
I got the Kuramae hot chocolate
there’s a huge line if you want to sit inside the cafe
so I’m enjoying it at the park just outside
it’s definately a lot richer than normal hot chocolates in Japan
this is partly a cafe
but also a shop for handmade leather accessories
this shop had some interesting incense and candles
theres even a shop that specialises in masking tapes
they have all different kinds of colours and patterns
last shop for today
how cute is this reusable coffee filter
dinner is omurice
I got the mushroom omurice
today we’re headed to Tsukiji markets
I heard it’s super crowded lately
but there were a few shops I wanted to check out in this area
starting with this viral coffee shop
I came around 11 and thought the line didn’t seem too bad
but there is only 1 barista and 1 staff working
so the line ended up taking 1.5 hours
which is more than I would usually be willing to wait for coffee
but the staff were really friendly despite being so busy
and the coffee was honestly really good
the sweetness of the matcha balances really well with the bitter expresso
I would recommend coming right at opening to avoid the crowd
we were originally going to eat at the fish markets
but did not feel like lining up again
I’ll come back next time
but luckily there was another bakery I wanted to check out
you can register online to get a wait time
this bakery is where the famous salt bread originated
they have so many options here
I highly recommend trying the original shio pan and the mentaiko flavour
and the melon bread if you like something sweet
they were still warm from the oven
you can hear how crispy this is
100% would recommend
we just went shopping around Ginza afterwards
in Shibuya for some dinner
feels like ages since I last came here
we’re at a all you can eat wagyu place
they also have all you can eat side dishes
and drinks
the only downside is that you have to go to the counter to order everytime
but the beef tongue was the best part
it’s a rainy day here in Tokyo
we’ll be exploring Kappabashi today
but need some caffeine first
looks like hydrangea season is starting
but that also means the start of rainy season
the owner of this cafe used to work in New Zealand and Australia
so I had high hopes for the coffee
they were even playing a Australian radio station
he seems to have won a lot of awards too
the coffee was good as expected
I can’t say no to a carrot cake
this one was moist and not too sweet
now time to look around Kappa street
but do you know the story of the Kappa?
they are these Japanese water yokais
they look like a mix of a monkey and a turtle
with a bowl of water on it’s head
they are known to be frightening creatures
that pull victims under water to drown them
but they have one essential flaw...
and it’s that they are extremely polite
so if you bow to them they will bow back spilling the bowl of water on it’s head
this will rendered completely helpless
but the street itself is well known for it’s kitchenware
you can get some Japanese kitchenware at a really good price
they had so many unique designs
if you want to find cute plates and bowls I would highly recommend this place
the whole street is lined with these stores
had some great finds here
dilemma between matcha or another coffee
matcha has really been taking over recently
spending the afternoon doing some reading
heading to Shimokitazawa today
this area is well known for it’s vintage stores, cafes and bars
nooooo
the coffee shop I wanted to go to seems to be closed
but good thing one of my favourite coffee shops was nearby
always a good coffee here
it’s definitely ice coffee weather now
really needed this coffee
time for some thrifting
I feel like I always look around the same few shops when I’m here
trying on a few dresses
lunch menu is soup curry
there seems to be a lot of soup curry places in this area
you can customise everything from the spiciness to all the toppings
soup curry was one of my favourite foods I tried in Hokkaido
this one came pretty close
back to shopping
there are also a lot of cute stores like this in the area
needed another coffee
one of the main reasons I came here was to check out the record stores
I’ve been thinking of getting a record player recently
and I heard Japan is the best place to buy secondhand vinyls
this place had such a big range
was honestly a bit overwhelmed with where to start
this place was better organised
and had some newer records as well
time to get some dinner
we’re back in Asakusa area
didn’t know the back streets had so many restaurants and bars
my friend recommended this place for kushikatsu
all the food was so good and affordable
the fried natto was the best
hope you guys enjoyed my second week here in Tokyo
see you in the next video :)